I will call it the regular skater made in my city council for two today for 23rd, 2026.
But again, put on skater personal appearances. We have none. 3A claims list.
3B minutes for the January 20th, 2026, regular meeting.
Second.
Five, five, two, five.
Five.
Three C.
Budget amendment 26.
Five.
Recreation using Cariover for skate park design.
Library receipt and expense state aid.
And senior center moving funds from 501C3 to senior center department.
So this is just some more general housekeeping as we clean up the books.
The senior center voted to move the 501C3 money to the city to allow us to spend
on city expenses so that received that money and basically sports and
racks I think is working on skate park things.
So that was some leftover money from last year that we're receiving and moving to
the new year and then the library just got a new grant.
So that just brings that money in.
Make motion.
Second.
Thank you.
All right.
3D appointment of Tyler Con and then Crystal Irick.
As the 2026 representatives to the grant gateway board of directors.
Congratulations.
For a one year term beginning February 1st, 2026.
I'm kind of hurt.
Motion to approve.
Okay.
Hi.
Hi. Hey Melinda.
Make sure you do a big press release on that.
So I hear this is a big deal.
Yeah.
3E vote on the city of my emergency operations plan which we are from
going to earlier.
Motion to approve.
Hi.
3F resolution.
MSU-826-022 and CC-026-025 for transportation alternatives grant project.
Application and maintenance commitment was Tyler talked about.
Okay.
Hi.
4.
Our new business of any of which has a business that's supposed to be this agenda.
5.
Staff reports.
We got.
5A and 5B. 5A is approved. The facility fee waiver and B is January sales and use tax.
I'll make motion approved.
What is that put in the back?
Six mayor council community announcements.
Yeah, I want to thank the Street Department and the rest of the city employees.
I think they did a fantastic job of clearing snow and ice from the roadways.
The school was clear and looked really good this year because of Robert and his crew going out there and playing it.
I just want to say thank you.
They did a great job.
As usual.
As a usual member of that part.
It's pretty good.
I heard there were streets that had never been done before.
It was nice to hear.
I'll follow along with these guys.
I've got normally a few times like this.
We'll get some negative comments from people.
I didn't get those.
I got a lot of positive comments from people.
Which is pretty exciting because I think the community is starting to believe that we actually do have their best interest in hard.
I don't think they believe that for a long time.
But I got a lot of comments from business owners downtown.
Thank you for doing the sidewalks.
I had a few people reach out and say hey, my road didn't get done and give me that address.
I had to get a drawer and then they'd get there and get it done.
But when they're doing that, that means roads.
They're going to miss one every once in a while.
But people were very understandable about it.
And when they asked, we went and took care of it.
And then they couldn't be more pleased.
So that all gets done by you guys.
And I know it's a full team effort.
Everybody asked the pile on.
And we never hear it's not my job.
You guys just get it done and we appreciate that.
And it did scare me you been in the truck.
I just rode.
I was a buffer.
And we did scare me.
You been in there too.
We did do.
We did.
We did do something.
Huh?
You're up.
We did.
We did do something.
I was out.
Brad Williams used to be one of our councilmen.
We went with the plout truck and plop a big pile of snow right in his driveway.
We did go back and take it out.
But we had a calling first.
His wife was not very happy.
She'd see about the snowplug guys.
They don't hurt.
But now we appreciate all of you because it wouldn't run without you.
And chief, I know your guys were out about it.
And I know Shannon and you guys were out in it stuff.
So everybody came out with safe and sound, which is always good.
So we appreciate all of you guys.
No.
He's probably going to talk about it right now.
Okay.
Seven, so you made a communication. Yes, two things later with the board now, so the fire department died at that recently came to us
And kind of ask K can we go on a six-month trial. There's a lot of
Part of our own surround here to do two consecutive days 24 our shifts on nine six-hour shifts off
So can we try four six-month time period
And you know, create a change in and send you got together and you know
They kind of worked with the numbers. It was an ecosystem or money. So
We're going to try and see how it goes. I mean, it's like think I think maybe it's a positive equivalent to all of that fair
to see
There's pros and cons and all this
Recruitment told up a probe
Studies as show within the first 72 hours. It's dramatic then
It lingers in your brain, which you know a little bit of and
Mental health in the issue with everyone and it's how people deal with it
Certain people deal with mental health different ways, but that 72 hour period gives him time to
Debrit their selves or to forget what you know
Happened so that 96 or that 96 hours will help that commute
Know there 48 hours that helps to a little bit
The cons you're there 48 hours in the row you might catch busy shift
But we're not going to I mean it's a if they catch an all-nighter than you know
We're we're going and we're not going to be
Sticklers about you got to get up
You know push push push push
So I
If I was back on the shift I would definitely be open about this. I think it's a really good thing
But patients would be awesome
Yeah, they they can take a vacation and receive
10 shifts all or 10 days in a row off. That's that's another probe
You know you're you you're going to get pushed back on all of it. It's good and bad
But it's worth looking at I think that our
Recruitment is a good thing
There's a couple tribes in order to do it there's the local
Like
Coal pollination they do it they said their older people was just totally against it didn't want nothing to do with it
And then after six months that they worked the firefighters and officers and the captains they
They did work the 24 hour shifts and they said hey, we want some of that too
So they're all doing it 48 96
Weatherford, Oklahoma
I talked to a couple people in St. Louis and they were totally against it
But now they're doing it. So I mean it's it's worth
How did your guys vote? I'm not a voted for it. Was it unanimous or it was close?
Yeah, was it the older guys that the older guys are pushing but and I don't blame them
Well, I mean
Heck if I had 30 years in and I have to do that schedule or change that absolutely I wouldn't like that
But like I told the older guys
We're doing it for the future and you know, and the future once it
So we're trying to handle coverage with call-ins on our 48-hour shift versus 24-hour
What will happen?
The tagging or the the cash hiring when hiring cash each 24-hour portion for the
Exhip will be filled separately. So that one guy will not get hit he won't work
Like
34 consecutive shifts in a row. It will be what we call a tax system. It's a mandatory over time
And
That shift needs covered well, they will tag the guy
Leading when the they will tag the tag the
The guy that's on shift prior to that shift and then if he's going to be gone the next
24-hour shift
the
Firefighter that left he will be on call until seven in the morning
For the tag system after seven he's released. He's on to that tag system. What's the longest and a firefighter's expected to work they can only work three days
It's what we're trying to yeah, so they're not overworked
I hope I'm making this clear. I mean, I'm not very good communicator
I'm off for it. That's what the guy's long thing it would and like he said it was close
Logged over guys and maybe it would be a different story of certain people would have showed up to the meeting and
But cast it there, but
Is what it is six months
six months trawled starting April
Second and go until September 30th and
We could shut it down any time that there's any issues or anything that she's full
Nope no more this do us I mean, it's like I think it's a neat thing
Like everything else new
Will they revoked themselves internally?
Will L and plus in the sheet they'll go over
They'll have meetings will have monthly meetings every month power things going
What you know and then they'll vote on after the six months
And there's no change of money, no loss of money, no equity.
It's just you're taking four days off, working two straight shifts, and then getting four days off.
The second thing is, as we had a really good meeting with our city staff,
Julia Tripe, and Quintripe.
So they have a new site plan.
They presented us our site plan yesterday.
They asked for some help for the COTA approvals.
I mean, it is good that the other site plan designed.
So we just have a spot for an extra restaurant, which would be cool.
So just like I've been able to click to this coming,
it's just, you know, there.
We got to get some things approved by ODOT, and I'm going to see it.
So everybody updated them.
It's a huge thing for mine.
So I think, oh, like everybody knows what it's going to be on.
You love Quintripe, right?
Yeah.
How many years you worked there?
How many years did you work?
How many years did you work there?
Yeah.
But then it's a...
I see you.
Yes, I'm pretty sure.
Item 8-12 will be starting.
We will not be going to take a session.
So 13 in German.
Thank you.
Bye.